KATE RUSSELL

269-362-4098 • <u>katerussell@sbcglobal.net</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/kateruss</u>

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

More than 20 years of experience in customer service and administrative positions in high-profile organizations in the corporate, technology, legal, banking, and education industries · Write and edit in traditional and new media formats · Oversee major institutional projects ·

 $Handle\ confidential\ materials \cdot Experience\ in\ bringing\ planning,\ organization,\ and\ structure\ to\ seeming\ chaos$

RELEVANT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UNIVERSITY OF NOTRE DAME, Notre Dame, Ind.—Information Architect and Client Support Agent, Marketing Communications, 2005 to Present (and 2000 to 2003)

- Develop training materials and train clients in Conductor, Notre Dame's proprietary CMS (including training by Skype for international clients)
- Web help contact and liaison
- Advise and educate clients as to best practices for Web content
- Brainstorm and collaborate on branding initiatives: create names, titles, and taglines for various products, programs, and units
- Research data for major projects and special events
- Create, write, and edit online content
- Created editorial style manual for the institution
- Review current websites for clients and prepare content inventory; prepare information
 architecture and wireframes for new or revamped sites; test sites for usability

MICROSOFT CORPORATION, Seattle, Wash.—Manager of Shareholder Services 1983–88

- Educated optionees regarding exercise of stock options and tax-bonus incentive
- Made internal stock transfers
- Handled confidential materials
- Oversaw conversion to new tracking software systems and debugging
- Coordinated shareholder meetings, including working with proxy solicitor
- Prepared stock options and coordinated stock splits with transfer agent
- Obtained securities and insurance licenses for selling stock

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Learning JavaScript, CSS, HTML, and WordPress
- Conductor CMS
- Microsoft Office products
- Teamwork and Workamajig project management software
- InDesign
- Social media, including Twitter, Facebook, HipChat
- FaceTime and Skype

EDUCATION

Ohio University: Certificate in Information Design, April 2011

University of Notre Dame: Coursework in writing and literature, Master of Science in Administration, and XHTML **Bethel College:** B.S. in organizational management

PUBLICATIONS

Presentations

"Web Content Best Practices to Share with Clients," Oct. 11, 2010, at HighEdWeb, Cincinnati

Trainer for Conductor, Notre Dame's proprietary content management system

Editing

Copy editor for Notre Dame's *Undergraduate Bulletin*, nd.edu, and other University websites, ND Forum materials (Web and print), *President's Newsletter, Rec Magazine*, and other University materials

Writing

Freelance article and short story writing · Conductor User Guide (conductor.nd.edu/user-guide/) · Web Musings blog (http://blogs.nd.edu/web-musings/ — no longer published) · Training materials for proprietary content management system

Relevant Skills/Experience

- CMS Customer Support
- Coordinate shareholder and athletics meetings and events
- Web writing and editing
- Daily interaction/ coordination with designers and developers
- Insatiable desire to continue learning
- Experience in and desire to be on cutting edge